Guide to the Harols Hotelling Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Harold Hotelling Papers,
1910-1975
Hotelling, Harold, 1895-
ca. 12800 items (57 boxes).
Columbia University Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Butler Library, New York, NY 10027.
4078401
Biographical Note
Harold Hotelling, 1895-1973, mathematical statistician and mathematical economist, taught at Columbia University from 1931 until he left in 1946 to establish the Institute of Statistics at the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill. During the Second World War Hotelling did research in Columbia University's Statistical Research Group. Later he was involved in research for the Office of Naval Research at Chapel Hill. He was active in many professional organizations, especially the Institute of Mathematical Statistics.
Scope and Content
Correspondence, manuscripts, addresses, documents and printed materials. Correspondents include: Milton Friedman, Samuel S. Wilks, Nathan Pusey, William Proxmire, Helen M. Walker, Ray Lyman Wilbur, Alfred Cowles, 3d and Ragnar Frisch. The papers also include biographical, teaching and research materials; publications and drafts of articles and books including his study, "The Teaching of Statistics," and materials on the concept of "Hotelling's Generalized T."
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into 12 series:
Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
Series II: Arranged Correspondence
Series III: Personal Correspondence
Series IV: Addresses/Memos
Series V: Organizations
Series VI: Manuscripts
Series VII: Research Data
Series VIII: Titled Problems
Seris IX: Miscellaneous Problems
Series X: Lectures and Courses
Series XI: Employment and Biographical
Series XII: Printed Material
Subjects
United States.--Office of Naval Research.; Institute of Mathematical Statistics.; Columbia University.--Statistical Research Group.; University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill.--Institute of Statistics.; University of North Carolina (Chapel Hill Campus). Department of Statistics.; Wilks, S. S. (Samuel Stanley), 1906-1964.; Friedman, Milton, 1912-; Pusey, Nathan Marsh, 1907-; Proxmire, WIlliam.; Wilbur, Ray Lyman, 1875-1949.; Mathematical statistics.; Economics, mathematical.; Statistics--study and teaching.
Access Restrictions
This collection has no restrictions.
The following boxes are located off-site: 2-58. You will need to request this material from the Rare Book and Manuscript Library at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
Acquisition
1985 Papers Hotelling, Mrs. Harold Gift
Gift of Mrs. Harold Hotelling, 1985.
- Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
  - Bowley, Arthur K. (Box 1)
  - Bundy, McGeorge (Box 1)
  - Cain, Harry P. (Box 1)
  - Camp, Burton H. (Box 1)
  - Cowles, Alfred, 3rd (Box 1)
  - Crane, Robert T. (Box 1)
  - Debye, Peter (Box 1)
  - Eisenhart, Luther Pfahler (Box 1)
  - Flexner, Abraham (Box 1)
  - Fisher, Irving (Box 1)
  - Friedman, Milton (Box 1)
  - Frisch, Ragnar (Box 1)
  - Glover, James (Box 1)
  - Graham, Frank P. (Box 1)
  - Graves, Lawrence M. (Box 1)
  - Kelley, Truman L. (Box 1)
  - Mayer, Joseph (Box 1)
  - Mills, Frederick C. (Box 1)
  - Odum, Howard W. (Box 1)
  - Pearson, Egon S. (Box 1)
  - Proxmire, William (Box 1)
  - Pusey, Nathan M. (Box 1)
  - Richardson, Roland George Dwight (Box 1)
  - Sachs, Alexander (Box 1)
  - Sanford, Terry (Box 1)
  - Schultz, Henry (Box 1)
  - Smith, Walter L. (Box 1)
  - Spurr, William A. (Box 1)
  - Taylor, James S. (Box 1)
  - Thompson, James S. (Box 1)
  - Van Sickle, John V. (Box 1)
  - Walker, Helen M. (Box 1)
  - Watkins, Ralph J. (Box 1)
  - Weaver, Warren (Box 1)
  - Wheeler, John A. (Box 1)
  - Wilbur, Ray Lyman (Box 1)
  - Wilks, Samuel S. (Box 1)
  - Wilson, Edwin B. (Box 1)
- Series II: Arranged Correspondence
  - A Miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - B Miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Barr, A.S. (Box 2)
  - Book Binding (Box 2)
  - Bartlett, M.S. (Box 2)
  - Bernhard, A. (Box 2)
  - Bose, R.C. (Box 2)
  - C Miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Camp, B.H. (Box 2)
  - Chu, J.T. (Box 2)
  - Cochran, W.G. (Box 2)
  - Cox, G. (Box 2)
  - D Miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Deming, W.E (Box 2)
  - Dwyer, P.S. (Box 2)
  - E Miscellaneous (Box 3)
  - F Miscellaneous (Box 3)
  - Factor Analysis (Box 3)
  - Fisher, R.A. (Box 3)
  - Flores, A.M. (Box 3)
  - G Miscellaneous (Box 3)
  - Ghurye, S.G. (Box 3)
  - Grubbs, F.E. (Box 3)
  - Gupta, S.S. (Box 3)
  - H Miscellaneous (Box 3)
  - Hicks, J.R (Box 3)
  - Hoeffding, W. (Box 3)
  - Hsu, P.L. (Box 3)
  - I Miscellaneous (Box 3)
  - Ito, P.K. (Box 3)
  - J Miscellaneous (Box 3)
  - K Miscellaneous (Box 3)
  - Katz, L. (Box 3)
  - Kelley, T.L. (Box 3)
  - Kendall, M.G. (Box 3)
  - King, A.K. (Box 4)
  - Koopmans, T. (Box 4)
  - Kozakiewicz, W. (Box 4)
  - Krishnaiah, P.R. (Box 4)
  - L Miscellaneous (Box 4)
  - M Miscellaneous (Box 4)
  - Madow, W.G. (Box 4)
  - Mahalanobis, P.C. 1938-1944 (Box 4)
  - Mahalanobis, P.C. (Box 4)
  - Mahalanobis, Snedecor, King, Panikar (Box 4)
  - Marsaglia, G. (Box 4)
  - Mc Miscellaneous (Box 4)
  - Mittra, P.C. (Box 4)
  - Morrison, N. (Box 4)
  - Morrow, D.J. (Box 4)
  - N Miscellaneous (Box 4)
  - Neyman, J. (Box 4)
  - 0 Miscellaneous (Box 5)
  - Ogawa, J. (Box 5)
  - P Miscellaneous (Box 5)
  - Passport Correspondence & Security Staff, 1953 & 1954 (Box 5)
  - Peach, P. (Box 5)
  - Pfouts, W.R. (Box 5)
  - Pitman, E.J.G. (Box 5)
  - Political Letters (Box 5)
  - Preinreich, G.A.D. (Box 5)
  - Q Miscellaneous (Box 5)
  - R Miscellaneous (Box 5)
  - Robbins, H.E. (Box 5)
  - Roodkowsky, N.D. (Box 5)
  - Roy, S.N. (Box 5)
  - Rubin, E. (Box 5)
  - S Miscellaneous (Box 5)
  - Stacy, E.W. (Box 5)
  - Schuyler, G.L. (Box 5)
  - Smith, J.D. (Box 5)
  - Solomon, H. (Box 5)
  - T Miscellaneous (Box 6)
  - Thomson, G.H. (Box 6)
  - U Miscellaneous (Box 6)
  - V Miscellaneous (Box 6)
  - W Miscellaneous (Box 6)
  - Wald, A. (Box 6)
  - Wallis, W.A. (Box 6)
  - Wallis-Fry (Box 6)
  - Wolfowitz, J. (Box 6)
  - Y-Z Miscellaneous (Box 6)
- Series III: Personal Correspondence
  - A-G (Box 7)
  - H-Z (Box 7)
  - Condolences: A-H (Box 7)
  - Condolences: J-Z (Box 7)
  - Memorial Letters, Material (Box 7)
  - Christmas and Sympathy cards (Box 7)
- Series IV: Addresses/Memos
  - Address List (index cards) (Box 8)
  - Addresses (Box 8)
  - Mailing list for Reprints (index cards) (Box 8)
  - Memos (notes, scratchwork) (Box 8)
- Series V: Organizations/Publications
  - American Associations for the Advancement of Science (Box 9)
  - AAAS Fisher Memorial Committee (Box 9)
  - American Association of University Professors (Box 9)
  - American Journal of Economics and Sociology (Box 9)
  - American Statistical Association (Box 9)
  - ASA Committee of Fellows - Details as to Candidates (Box 9)
  - Annals of Mathematical Statistics (Box 9)
  - American Mathematical Society (Box 10)
  - Air Force Meeting, 7 May 1963 (Box 10)
  - Air Research and Development (Box 10)
  - Courant Committee (Box 10)
  - Reports and Correspondence (3) (Box 10)
  - Carnegie Corporation of New York Grants (Box 11)
  - Applicants Who Never Held These Grants (Box 11)
  - Financial Reports of Work Done Under Grants (Box 11)
  - Keppel, Dollard, Lester, Jessup (correspondence) (Box 11)
  - Past Holders of Grants (Box 11)
  - Reports (Box 11)
  - Columbia University Clairvoyance, Telepathy: Matching Distribution (Box 12)
  - Columbia University Correspondence (Box 12)
  - Columbia University Economics Department (Box 12)
  - Columbia University Fellowship and Assistantship Applications (Box 12)
  - Columbia University Funding Information and Requests (Box 12)
  - Columbia University Graduate Record Exam (Box 12)
  - Columbia University Parapsychology (Box 12)
  - Columbia University Statistical Research Grop (S.R.G.) Administration (Box 12)
  - Columbia University S.R.G Alternatives to T (Box 12)
  - Columbia University S.R.G Bombsights Atlantic City (Box 12)
  - Columbia University S.R.G. Bombsight Accuracy £1 (Box 12)
  - Columbia University S.R.G. Bombsight £2 (Box 12)
  - Columbia University S.R.G Charts (Box 12)
  - Columbia University S.R.G Memoranda Within Group (Box 12)
  - Columbia University Students (Box 12)
  - Econometric Society (2) (Box 13)
  - Econometrica (Box 13)
  - Elisha Mitchell Society (Box 13)
  - Ford Foundation Advisory Committee (2) (Box 13)
  - General Electric Company (Box 13)
  - Havard University Ad Hoc Committee (Box 13)
  - Institute for International Education (Box 13)
  - Institute of Mathematical Statistics, To Dec. 31, 1941 (Box 14)
  - Institute of Mathematical Statistics Agendas (Box 14)
  - Institute of Mathematical Statistics Committee on History of Statistics (Box 14)
  - Institute of Mathematical Statistics Committee on Teaching and Placement of Statisticians Correspondence (4) (Box 14)
  - Institute of Mathematical Statistics Draft for National Roster Organization (Box 14)
  - Institute of Mathematical Statistics Organization (Box 14)
  - I.M.S Committee on the Teaching of Statistics Correspondence (Box 15)
  - I.M.S Committee on the Teaching of Statistics Memoranda (Box 15)
  - I.M.S Committee on the Teaching of Statistics Memoranda/Correspondence (Box 15)
  - I.M.S Committee on the Teaching of Statistics Pre-1944 (Box 15)
  - I.M.S Committee on the Teaching of Statistics Proposals for Statistical Institute, Columbia University (Box 15)
  - I.M.S Committee on the Teaching of Statistics Report, 1947 (Box 15)
  - I.M.S Committee on the Teaching of Statistics Reports (2) (Box 15)
  - I.M.S Committee on the Teaching of Statistics Southern Regional Education Board (Box 15)
  - Institute National D'Etude du Travail (Box 16)
  - Institute for Research in Social Science (2) (Box 16)
  - Institute of Statistics (Box 16)
  - International Congress of Mathematicians (Box 16)
  - Inter-American Statistical Institute (Box 16)
  - International Encyclopaedia of Social Sciences (Box 16)
  - International Statistical Institute (2) (Box 17)
  - International Statistical Institute Conference, 1960 (Box 17)
  - International Statistical Institute Conference, 1961, 1967 (Box 17)
  - Journal of the American Statistical Association (Box 17)
  - National Academy of Sciences (Box 17)
  - National Recovery Administration (Box 17)
  - National Science Foundation (Box 17)
  - Personnel Journal (Box 17)
  - Princeton Bicentennial: Problems of Mathematics, Dec. 1946 (Box 17)
  - U.S. Office of Naval Research Appointments (Box 18)
  - U.S. Office of Naval Research Contract and Renewal Applications (Box 18)
  - U.S. Office of Naval Research Correspondence (Box 18)
  - U.S. Office of Naval Research European Trip, 1953 (Box 18)
  - U.S. Office of Naval Research European Trip, 1957 (Box 18)
  - U.S. Office of Naval Research Finances and Plans (Box 18)
  - U.S. Office of Naval Research Miscellaneous (Box 18)
  - U.S. Office of Naval Research Operating Rules (Box 18)
  - U.S. Office of Naval Research Personnel (Box 18)
  - U.S. Office of Naval Research Problems (Box 18)
  - U.S. Office of Naval Research Reports, 1947-52 (Box 19)
  - U.S. Office of Naval Research Reports, 1953-1959 (Box 20)
  - U.S. Office of Naval Research Miscellaneous (Box 20)
  - U.S. Civil Service Commission (Box 21)
  - U.S. Office of Scientific Personnel (Box 21)
  - Watumull Foundation (Box 21)
  - Publishers (Box 21)
  - Statistical Organizatons Meetings, Conferences (Box 21)
  - University of North Carolina Administrative Transportation (Box 22)
  - University of North Carolina Advisory committee (Box 22)
  - University of North Carolina Appointments (Box 22)
  - University of North Carolina Book Exchange (Box 22)
  - University of North Carolina Budget: general, 1946 & 1947 (Box 22)
  - University of North Carolina Budget: general, 1947-1951 (Box 22)
  - University of North Carolina Correspondence (Box 22)
  - University of North Carolina Courses, 1948 & 1949 (Box 22)
  - University of North Carolina Department Meetings (Box 22)
  - University of North Carolina Departmental Reports (Box 22)
  - University of North Carolina European Trips, 1951 & 1953 (Box 22)
  - University of North Carolina Fellowship Information and Correspondence (Box 22)
  - University of North Carolina Fellowship and Assistantship Applications, 1956 (Box 22)
  - University of North Carolina Graduate Council and Administrative Board (Box 22)
  - University of North Carolina Grad. S-Z (Box 23)
  - University of North Carolina Grad Students (Box 23)
  - University of North Carolina Graduate Programs for Statistics Majors, Regional Conference on Statistics. R, VA (Box 23)
  - University of North Carolina Mathematical Statistics, Applications for Graduate Appointment, 1948 (Box 23)
  - University of North Carolina Memoranda (Box 23)
  - University of North Carolina Miscellaneous Directories (Box 23)
  - University of North Carolina New Building (Box 23)
  - University of North Carolina North Carolina State College, 1941 (Box 23)
  - University of North Carolina Offices and Office Furniture (Box 23)
  - University of North Carolina PhD Candidates (Box 23)
  - University of North Carolina Publicity (Box 23)
  - University of North Carolina Publicity - Future (Box 23)
  - University of North Carolina Sabbatical Leave (Box 23)
  - University of North Carolina Salary Policies (Box 23)
  - University of North Carolina Statistics Department (Box 23)
  - University of North Carolina Statistics Department Directories (Box 23)
  - University of North Carolina Statistics for Students Outside Regular Graduate Group (Box 23)
  - University of North Carolina University Research Funds (Box 23)
  - University of North Carolina War Problems (Box 23)
  - University of North Carolina Working Rules (Box 23)
  - University of North Carolina Statistics Colloquium (Box 24)
  - University of North Carolina Correspondence (Box 24)
  - University of North Carolina Institute of Statistics, 1945, 1946 and earlier (Box 24)
  - University of North Carolina Air Force - Design of Experiments (Box 24)
  - University of North Carolina Air Force - Multivariate (Box 24)
  - University of North Carolina Army Air Force Problems (Box 24)
  - University of North Carolina Cloud Seeding (Box 24)
  - University of North Carolina Early Planning (Box 24)
- Series VI: Manuscripts
  - Subseries VI.1: Works by Hotelling
    - Analysis of a Complex of Statistical Variables in Prinical Components (Box 25)
    - The Behavior of Some Standard Statistical Tests Under Non-Standard Conditions (Box 25)
    - Causes of Birth Rate Fluctuations (Box 25)
    - Correlation (Box 25)
    - The Correlation Coefficient and Its Transformations: A New Look (Box 25)
    - Cycles and Forecasts (Box 25)
    - Depreciation (Box 25)
    - Different Meanings of Experimental Design (Box 25)
    - Dr Perters' Criticism of Fisher's Statistics (Box 25)
    - Econometric Paper No. 19-B (Box 25)
    - Effect of a Tax on the Price of an Isolated Monopolized Article (Box 25)
    - The Efficiency of the Sample Median (Box 25)
    - Fitting an Mixture of Two Univariate Normal Distributions by the Method of Moments .. (Box 25)
    - Future Research Workers Need Mathematics Now (Box 25)
    - A Generalized T Measure of Multivariate Dispersion (Box 25)
    - The General Welfare, to 1938 (Box 25)
    - The Impact of R.A. Fisher on Statistics (Box 26)
    - Mathematical Economics (Box 26)
    - The Mathematical Training of Social Scientists (Box 26)
    - The Measure of the Hypersphere and Its Interior (Box 26)
    - Memorandum on the Science of Statistics (Box 26)
    - The Moments of the Sample Median (Box 26)
    - The Moniac (Box 26)
    - More Research Needed Here (Box 26)
    - The Most Predictable Criterion (Box 26)
    - Multivariate Analysis (Box 26)
    - Multivariate Methods on Testing Complex Eqipment (Box 26)
    - Multiple Partial Correlation (Box 26)
    - New Light on the Correlation Coefficient and Its Transforms (Box 26)
    - New State Tax (Box 26)
    - Note on Matric Theorem of A. Craig (Box 26)
    - On the Nature of Supply and Demand Functions, et al (Box 26)
    - The Place of Statistics in the University (Box 26)
    - Problems of Prediction (Box 26)
    - Professor I. Fisher's Proposed Income Tax Revision (Box 26)
    - Prosperity Through Increased Production (Box 26)
    - Rank Correlations, etc, 1935 & 1936 (Box 26)
    - Relations Between Two Sets of Variates, 1936 (Box 26)
    - Relations of the Newer Multivariate Statistical Method to Factor Analysis (Box 26)
    - H. Schultz as Economist (Box 27)
    - Sir Ronald Fisher 1890 - 1963, the Early Years (Box 27)
    - Some Mathematical Contributions to Economics, (Max.Min.) (Box 27)
    - Some New Methods in Matrix Calculation (Box 27)
    - Statistical Inference(2) (Box 27)
    - Statistical Theory (Box 27)
    - Stochastic Processes and Difference Equations (Box 27)
    - Summary of the Scientific Activity of G. Leti (Box 27)
    - Tubes in n-space (Box 27)
    - Utility Functions and Applications (Box 27)
    - Why We Have the Two-Party System (Box 27)
  - Subseries VI.2: Works by others (by author)
    - Agricultural Economics (Conference) (Box 28)
    - Allais, M. (Box 28)
    - American Standard Association (Box 28)
    - Anderson, T.T. (Box 28)
    - Army Air Force Training Command (Box 28)
    - Atchinson, W.F. (Box 28)
    - Bain (Box 28)
    - Bargman, R (Box 28)
    - Bechhofer, R.E. et al (Box 28)
    - Berger, A. and Gold, R. (Box 28)
    - Bowker, A. (Box 28)
    - Bradley, R.A. and Terry, M.E. (Box 28)
    - Brown, F.F. and Masket, A.V. (Box 28)
    - Byl, A. (Box 28)
    - Carlson, J.L. (Box 29)
    - Chacko, G.K. (Box 29)
    - Churchman, C.W. (Box 29)
    - Committee on the Teaching of Statitics (Box 29)
    - Cowan, T.A. (Box 29)
    - Cowles, A. (Box 29)
    - Crutcher, H.L. (Box 29)
    - Debreu, G. (Box 29)
    - Demand for Related Goods (Box 29)
    - Divisia, F. (Box 29)
    - Dorfman, R. (Box 29)
    - Dugue, D. (Box 29)
    - Duncan, D.B. (Box 29)
    - Emmons, H.W. (Box 30)
    - Eyraud, D.H. (Box 30)
    - Fand, D.I. (Box 30)
    - Frankel, L. and Stock, J.S. (Box 30)
    - Freeman, H. (Box 30)
    - Frisch, R. (Box 30)
    - Furbush, M. (Box 30)
    - Geisser, S. (Box 30)
    - Halperin, M. (Box 30)
    - Hamilton, C.H. (Box 30)
    - Hildreth, C. (Box 30)
    - Hoeffding, W. (Box 30)
    - Horton, W.H. (Box 30)
    - Houthakker, H.S. (Box 30)
    - Hunter, J.S. (Box 30)
    - Hutt, W.H. (Box 30)
    - Ihm, P. (Box 30)
    - Institute of Statistics (Box 30)
    - Johnson, R.B. (Box 31)
    - Jones, L.K. (Box 31)
    - Kaiser, H.F. (Box 31)
    - Kempthorne, 0. (Box 31)
    - Kettenring, J.R. (Box 31)
    - Kimball, B.F. (Box 31)
    - Koopmans, T. (Box 31)
    - Latane, H.A. (Box 31)
    - Location of Competitors (Box 31)
    - Lord, F.M. (Box 31)
    - Lucas, H.L. (Box 31)
    - Lum, Mary D. (Box 31)
    - McKenzie, L.W. (Box 31)
    - Meany, G. and Thomas, R.J. (Box 31)
    - Mudgett, B.D. (Box 31)
    - Morrison, D.F. (Box 31)
    - Morrison, N. (2) (Box 32)
    - Morrow, D.J. (Box 32)
    - Murthy, V.K. (Box 32)
    - National Research Council (Box 32)
    - N.Y. State Public Service Commission (Box 32)
    - Nicholson (Box 32)
    - Ogawa, J. (2) (Box 32)
    - Olkin (Box 32)
    - Payne, L.E. et al (Box 32)
    - Pfouts, R.W. (Box 32)
    - Price, D.O. (Box 32)
    - Roodkowsky, N.D. and Thorndike, R.L. (5) (Box 33)
    - Roy, S.N. (Box 33)
    - Simon, H.A (Box 33)
    - Sistani, M. (Box 33)
    - Smith, W.L. (Box 33)
    - Social Science Research Council (Box 33)
    - Southern Bell Telephone & Telegraph Co. (Box 33)
    - Stacy, E.W. (Box 33)
    - Stein, C. (Box 33)
    - Stuart, A. (Box 33)
    - Tufts College (Box 33)
    - Uspensky, J.V. (Box 33)
    - Wald, A. (Box 33)
    - Walker, V.W. (Box 33)
    - Wilks, S.S. (Box 33)
    - Williams, E. (Box 33)
    - Wilson, E.B. (Box 33)
    - Yang, Chung-How (Box 33)
  - Subseries VI.3: Chapters from Hotelling's Books
    - Chapter 1 (5): (drafts and research) (Box 34)
    - Chapter 2 (2) (Box 35)
    - Chapter 3 (Box 35)
    - Chapter 4 (Box 35)
    - Chapter 5 (Box 35)
    - Chapters 5-7 (Box 35)
    - Chapter 6 (Box 35)
    - Chapter 7 (Box 35)
    - Chapter 9 (3) (Box 36)
    - Chapter 10 (2) (Box 36)
    - Chapters 11-12 (Box 36)
    - Chapter 11 (3) (Box 36)
    - Chapter 12 (Box 37)
    - Chapter 13 (3) (Box 37)
    - Chapter 14 (2) (Box 37)
    - Chapter 15 (Box 37)
    - Chapter 16 (2) (Box 38)
    - Chapter 17 (Box 38)
    - Chapter 18 (Box 38)
    - Chapter 19 (Box 38)
    - Chapter 20 (Box 38)
    - Chapter 21 (2) (Box 39)
    - Chapter 22 (Box 39)
    - Chapter 23 (Box 39)
    - Chapter 24 (2) (Box 39)
    - Chapters 25-26 (Box 39)
    - Miscellaneous 1 - Least Squares (2) (Box 39)
    - Miscellaneous (2-5) (Box 39)
    - Reference for books (Box 40)
    - Bibliographies (Box 40)
    - Corrections (Box 40)
    - Footnote References (Box 40)
- Series VII: Research Data
  - Agriculture I, II, III, IV (Box 41)
  - Building Industry (Box 41)
  - Correlation Research, 1953 (Box 41)
  - Experimental Determination .. (Box 41)
  - Experiments in Coin Tossing (Box 41)
  - Hip Girth and Stature (Box 41)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 41)
  - Rare Mathematical Notes (Box 41)
  - Seattle Elections Data, 1910-1919 (Box 41)
  - T2 (Box 41)
- Series VIII: Titled Problems
  - Accelerated Iterative Calculation of Principal Components Analysis into Principal Components (Box 42)
  - Analysis into Principal Components: --1) Unpublished material ;--1) Calculations ;--1) Meetinf in December 1931 of Unitary Traits Committee (Box 42)
  - City Planning (Box 42)
  - Comparison of Two Tetrachoric Tables (Box 42)
  - Correlation with Incomplete Data (Box 42)
  - Couchy Distribution, esp (Box 42)
  - Calculations Relating to: "Differential Equations and Population Estimates" 1927 (Box 42)
  - Carious Teeth and Pregnancy, 1934 (Box 42)
  - Discriminant Functions (Box 42)
  - Distributions of Quadratic Forms (2) (Box 42)
  - Effects of Non-Normality (Box 42)
  - Exploitation of Irreplaceable Assets (Box 42)
  - Least Squares Problems of Col. Wm. F. Bark (Box 42)
  - Manifolds of Orthagonal ennuples (Box 43)
  - Methods of Matric Calculation (3) (Box 43)
  - Multiple R (Box 43)
  - Multivariate Analysis (Box 43)
  - Multivariate Periodogram Analysis (Box 44)
  - Multivariate Analysis of Variance (Box 44)
  - Population Problems (Box 44)
  - Sampling Errors of Trends (Box 44)
  - Selection of Predictors (Box 44)
  - Spaces of Statistical Parameter (Box 44)
  - Tinter, G. Various problems (Box 44)
  - The Transformation of Statistics (Box 44)
  - Truncated Normal Distributions (Box 44)
  - Volume of a Thin Tube in a Curved Space (Box 44)
- Seris IX: Miscellaneous Problems
  And 1 oversize folder
  - Miscellaneous Problems, 1923-1965 (Box 45)
  - Unsolved Problems (Box 45)
  - Miscellaneous Problems, undated, ((2) ) (Box 45)
- Series X: Lectures and Courses
  - Lectures by Hotelling (Box 46)
  - Lectures by Hotelling: Economics of Obsolescence and Research (Box 46)
  - Lectures (by others) (2) (Box 46)
  - Advanced Mathematical Economics (Box 47)
  - Advanced Mathematical Statistics (Box 47)
  - Approximation Techniques (Box 47)
  - Correlation, Contingency and x2 (Box 47)
  - Determinants and Matrices (Box 47)
  - Least Squares and Time Series (Box 47)
  - Least Squares and Time Series - Exams (Box 47)
  - Mathematical Economics (3) (Box 48)
  - Mathematical Theory of Probability and Statistics (Box 48)
  - Statistics (Box 48)
  - Statistical Inference, 1927 (Box 49)
  - Statistical Inference (Box 49)
  - Statistical Inference - Exams (Box 49)
  - Stochastic Process (Box 49)
  - Theses (Box 49)
  - Time Series Analysis (Box 49)
  - Exam Questions (Box 49)
  - Grade Reports (Box 49)
  - Photographs of Students (Box 49)
- Series XI: Employment and Biographical
  - Employment Opportunities (Box 50)
  - Misc. Personnel Problems (Box 50)
  - Prospective Personnel (Box 50)